Shaffick Ali

shaffickali16@gmail.com • 973-609-9849

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaffick-ali-227750207/

OBJECTIVE

Creative and goal-oriented communications professional seeking a position utilizing experience in social media, video editing, and marketing. Possess 3+ years of experience using social media for marketing purposes. Proven to understand viewer retention and analyze common trends.

EDUCATION

William Paterson University | Wayne, N.J

Bachelor of Arts in Communication | Broadcast Journalism Concentration

GPA: 3.6

RELATED COURSEWORK

Digital & Social Media Communication

January 2021- May 2021

- Created and grew social media account over 15 week semester
- Oversaw weekly analytics including the total number of likes, followers, or viewers
- Developed and created weekly content including graphics and videos to engage the audience
- Adapted content based on viewer analytics and engagement

Senior Capstone Project

January 2021- May 2021

- Created a 4 min video package on Should Athletes Be Paid
- Storyboarded questions for voice bytes
- Edited footage to grab audience attention

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Content Creator YouTube, Independent

November 2020- Present

- Edited footage that creates a story for viewer retraction around entertainment, sports, news
- Scheduled interviews with guests and maintains a tight schedule
- Created thumbnails and study common trends to increase viewership
- Grew channel to over 78,000+ channel views in the past 2 years
- Has surpassed 500 subscribers in 2 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

Burlington Coat Factory, Garfield, N.J.

August 2020 - September 2021

Loss Prevention Associate

- Interacted with customers about lost items, returns or other issues
- Secured lost items found within store until the rightful customer arrived

Walmart, Wimauma, FL

December 2021 - Present

Digital Personal Shopper

- Interacted with customers about lost items, returns or other issues
- Shopped personal orders and stored them in the correct sections

Shaffick Ali

 $\underline{shaffickali16@gmail.com} \bullet 973\text{-}609\text{-}9849$

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaffick-ali-227750207/

Technical Skills

Computers: Adobe Premiere, Excel, Adobe Creative, iMovie, CapCut and Canva

Languages: English (Native), Spanish (Conversational)